Guide to the Arturo Islas Papers, 1956-1991
Department of Special Collections
- Series 6: People Files
  - James R. Magee: poem, magazine article, and short story - Santa Fe Bridge, incoming and outgoing correspondence, poem by Islas - Finnish Archipelago/Island Poem I (1987) (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Mary Manning (1989):correspondence (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Kate McDonald (1987):short story - Dutch Cleanser, correspondence, poem (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Mary Moser: Mantra and Nirvana - poems by Islas (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Raymund Paredes (1985):correspondence and bibliography (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Francisco Pineiro (1990):letter, writing samples (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Florian Shasky (1988):correspondence (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Pat Soberanis (1990):letter from Islas, news clipping (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Gary Soto (1990):news clippings, incoming letter (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Maria Helen Viramontes (1981):correspondence and writing sample (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Graduate Admissions (Winter 1980):notes and ratings of applicants (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Admissions (Winter 1986):notes and ratings of applicants (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Francisco Alarcon: dissertation abstact (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Arturo Aldama (1987):correspondence (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Alicia Arrizon: outline for dissertation project, photocopied articles (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Judith Bare (1990):letter of recommendation, orals list, handouts, notes, writings (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Adam Begley: orals, orals list (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Mark Braley: letters of recommendation (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Barbara Brinson-Pineda (1986):letter of recommendation, statement of purpose, curriculum vitae (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Paulette Britton: orals and dissertaion info (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Mark Brommell (1983):orals reading list, correspondence, discussion questions (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Tisa Carrillo: dissertation abstract (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Wendell Carter (1986):memo, letter of recommendation, evaluation (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Alexandria Chasin (1986):letter of recommendation, evaluation, correspondence (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Joseph Conte (1986):letter (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Susan Denver: essays (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Rava Eleasari (1987):correspondence, orals list (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Paul Espinoza: NEH application and materials (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Vince Gotera: correspondence, letter of recommendation (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Paul Guajardo: correspondence (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Sergio Guerrero: correspondence, poetry (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - Franziska Herrmann (1987):correspondence (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - Black Poets - Pat Hill: Islas's notes, poetry, dissertation proposal, orals reading list (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Scott Lankford (1985-1988):curriculum vitae, statement of purpose, letter of recommendation, correspondence (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Sandy Lieb (1972-1988):correspondence, orals list, dissertation prospectus, miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - Wahneema Lubiano: curriculum vitae, correspondence, dissertation prospectus, essays (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Patricia McGraw: correspondence, essays, letter of recommendation (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Augustine Martinez: essay, letter (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - Richard May: memos, bibliography (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - Lindsay Mikolitch (1987-1988):correspondence (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - Brett Miller (1983-1985):poetry, orals list, correspondence, memos (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - Patricia Montenegro: poetry, dissertation report, essays (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - Trudy Palmer: correspondence, writing (Box 42, Folder 33)
  - Anita Smith Paradowski (1988):correspondence, thesis - Narrative Strategies In Three Multicultural Novels: The Woman Warrior, The Color Purple, and The Rain God (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - Johnny Payne: orals, orals list, notes (Box 42, Folder 35)
  - Gail Perez: essay - Hymns In a Man's Life: Styles and Cultures in D. H. Lawrence's Poetry (Box 42, Folder 36)
  - Rafael Perez-Torres (1987-1989):correspondence, orals info, parts of dissertation (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Vince Perez: orals list, correspondence (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Vincent Perez: memos, disseration info (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Febe Portillo (1987-1988):correspondence, President's Fellowship program application (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Febe Portillo Orozco: correspondence, letter of recommendation, orals list, etc. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Febe Portillo Orozco: thesis (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Catherine Quoyeser: curriculum vitae, letter of recommendation, orals information, writing excerpts (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Loren Rusk: orals information (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - John Russell (1987):letter (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Ben Saenz (1987-1989):letters of recommendation, correspondence, essays (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Ines Salazar: correspondence (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Josie Saldana (1988):qualifications information (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Jose Saldivar (1985-1987):curriculum vitae, letters of recommendation, incoming and outgoing correspondence, writings (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Jose Saldivar (1982-1986):correspondence, writings, grant applications (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Jose Saldivar: writing excerpts (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Roxannne Schroeder (1987):personal statement, resume, letter of recommendation (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Susan TePaske-King (1985):personal statemnt, letter of recommendation (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Gloria Trevino: correspondence, Fugitive (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Gloria Trevino: dissertation proposal, notes, writings (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Luis Urrea (1986):curriculum vitae, letter, Father Returns from the Mountain (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - John Williams (1987):essay and book reviews, 2 letters from Islas (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Helga Winkler (1985)correspondence (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Man Withington (1988):letter- A Testament to Life and Death: The Rain God by Islas (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Mary Wood (1984-1987):correspondence and dissertation proposal (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Diane Young (1984):orals reading list, poetry (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Bernice Zamora (1980-1986):notes, memos, correspondence with letters from Islas, and writing samples (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Miguel Baez (1976):recommendation, recommendation info (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Xavier Becerra (1980):resume, letter (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Nicole Bettauer (1985):letter, resume, letter of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Juan Bezanilla (1990):writing samples (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Kristen Boyles (1987):resume, letter, paper (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Cathy Bledsoe (1985-1988):resume, letters of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Elizabeth Burnside: letter of recommendation, resume (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Ethan Canin (1981):letter (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Eloisa Carrillo: personal statement (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Pedro Castillo: letter (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Luz Castillo: letter of recommendation, letter (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Melanie Celeste (1989):letter, Master of Liberal Studies Program Proposal (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Wayne Chavez (1990):writing samples (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Linda Christie (1987-1988):letters, resume (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Carol Cini (1985):grant proposal, honors essay proposal, letters (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Clarissa Clayton: letter of recommendation, personal statement, resume, letter (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Tim Conley (1979):letter of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Alberto Cota (1982-1983):letter of reference, resume (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Mark Davidian (1985):letter of recommendation, personal statement (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Isabel De La Pena (1983):letter of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Kevin Douglas (1984-1985):letters, letter of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Cynthia Ellis (1985):letter of recommendation, letters (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Richard Esquibel (1981-1985):letters from Sally Mahoney - re: registration (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Cynthia Franklin (1985):personal statement, letter of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Francesca Freccero (1984):letters - to and from, letter of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - David Freelove (1988):notes, letters, writing sample (Box 45, Folder 26)
  - Patricia Freytag (1983-1984):letters from the office of the Registrar (Box 45, Folder 27)
  - Yolanda Garcia (1985):letter (Box 45, Folder 28)
  - Cristina Gavin: letters, academic information (Box 45, Folder 29)
  - Lynn Goldfarb (1988):individually designed major information (Box 45, Folder 30)
  - Patrick Gomez: letters of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 31)
  - Adriana Graft (1986-1987):personal statement, resume, correspondence (Box 45, Folder 32)
  - Anne Gullickson (1985):Honors Thesis Proposal (Box 45, Folder 33)
  - Leah Halper (1980-1990):personal statement, correspondence, letter of recommendation, Stanford Daily clippings (Box 45, Folder 34)
  - Heather Hawkins (1987):resume, letter of recommendation, graduate school application (Box 45, Folder 35)
  - Julie Jacobs (1983):letter from Academic Information Center (Box 45, Folder 36)
  - Francisca James (1981):letter (Box 45, Folder 37)
  - Jennifer Justman (1980-1982):resume, writing samples, letter of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 38)
  - Chris Kelly (1980-1986):resume, letter of recommendation, course material (Box 45, Folder 39)
  - Sean Kinch (1989):letter (Box 45, Folder 40)
  - Mark Kindschuh: personal statement, resume, transcripts, writing samples (Box 45, Folder 41)
  - Madeline Kiser: project proposal (winter 1990) (Box 45, Folder 42)
  - Cynthia Ann Koehn (1979):major declaration (Box 45, Folder 43)
  - Shara Kronmal (1981):personal statement, writing samples, letter of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 44)
  - Robert Landon (1988):Golden Grant application (Box 45, Folder 45)
  - Michael Lara (1990):correspondence (Box 45, Folder 46)
  - Sara Lau: writing sample, correspondence, letter of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 47)
  - Laugh and Rose - Seminar/ Autumn 1981-1982:course material and info (Box 45, Folder 48)
  - Sarah Liu: letter of recommendation, correspondence, writing sample, Golden Grant applications material (Box 45, Folder 49)
  - Jesse Luna: writing samples (Box 45, Folder 50)
  - Lisa Lynch (1987):personal statement and letter of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 51)
  - Celina Martinez: writing samples (Box 45, Folder 52)
  - Alma Medina (1990):writing samples (Box 45, Folder 53)
  - Karin McDonald (1990):writing sample (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Monica Melgarejo (1981):Humanities Honors Program information (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Nicole Michaels (1986):incoming and outgoing correspondence (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Kimberly Mitchell (1987):correspondence (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Julie Morrisett: statement of purpose, writing sample, statement of purpose (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Barry Munger (1985):writing sample (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Jane Oglesby: writing sample (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Dennis Oh (1984):writing smaples, medical school application materials (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Nancy Orendain (1981):resume and letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Julie Padilla: writing samples (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Donnalisa Parks (1981-1983):resume, memos, letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Cynthia Parral: statement of purpose, letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Mark Peyser (1985):correspondence (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Margo Ponce (1990):writing sample, memos, research proposals (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Robert Prieto (1990):writing samples (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Regan Ramsey (1986):recommendation (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Dorotea Reyna (1979):writing samples, memoms, transcripts, letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Caroline Rhoads (1984):letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Ben Robinson (1988):letter (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Nicole Rosenberg (1983):writing sample (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Antoinieta Ruvalcava (1990):writing samples (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Rod Searcey (1986):letter and 2 photographs (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Reid Sherline (1987):letter (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Scott Simon (1982)Recent American Fiction course information (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Scott Singer (1989):letter (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - Mitch Skylar (1983):personal statement, resume (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Katie Smith (1982):letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Victor Solorza (1987):letter (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - Rob S. Spears (1984):letter and letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - John Strand (1986):correspondence, letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 30)
  - Karen Su (1987):letter, writing smaples, letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - Silvia Tandeciarz: writing samples, thesis proposal, letters (Box 46, Folder 32)
  - Joel Townsend (1984-1990):letter, letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 33)
  - Velina Underwood (1990):resume, personal statement, letter of recommendation, memo (Box 46, Folder 34)
  - Joseph Vaughn (1985):correspondence (Box 46, Folder 35)
  - John Walton (1984):letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 36)
  - Anastasia Watson (1983-1984):personal statement, letter of recommendation, writing sample (Box 46, Folder 37)
  - Robert Weisbach (1986):correspondence (Box 46, Folder 38)
  - Robyn Leigh Weisman (1987):incoming and outgoing correspondence (Box 46, Folder 39)
  - Jerry Wertheim (1983-1984):Humanities Honor Proposal, memos (Box 46, Folder 40)
  - Cindi Wheeler: memos, outlines for honors thesis (Box 46, Folder 41)
  - David Woo (1984):letter, letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 42)
  - Maggie Wright (1983):memos, academic information, writing sample (Box 46, Folder 43)
  - Karen Zacarias: letter, news article, proposal (Box 46, Folder 44)
  - Horacio Zambran: writing samples (Box 46, Folder 45)
  - Evelina Zuni-Lucerno (1986):resume, letter of recommendation (Box 46, Folder 46)
  - Other Undergraduate Work (1990) (Box 46, Folder 47)
  - Responses Required (1979-1982):student letter and student work (Box 46, Folder 48)
  - Student Work (1987, 1989) (Box 46, Folder 49)
- Series 7: Videotapes, Audiotapes, and Journals
  - Videotape: Jimmy Santiago Baca @ Stanford University reading, Jan. 16, 1989,Interview, Jan. 17, 1989,intro by Denise Levertov (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - videotapes: Cable Co-Ops Community Channel Six - Reading Writers with Arturo Islas, 58 minutes at SP (Box 47, Folder 2, 3, 4)
  - Audiotape: Chicano Literary Criticos... Conference, Stanford Universtiy, Saturday, May 30, 1987,Rosaura-? Sanchez on The Rain God and readings (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Journal: Twenty-four Hours a Day (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Journal: A Day at a Time (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Contents from cardfile (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1959-1964, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: dark green cover (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1967 - 1972, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: gray cover (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1973 - 1978, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: blue green cloth cover (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1975 - 1977, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: tan leather cover (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1989 - 1990, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: black cover (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Calendar, 1976, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v. (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - American dream and fantasies: calendar, 1977, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v. with loose ams leaves tipped in (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - The gay engagement calendar, 1978, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: orange cover, with loose ams leaves tipped in (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - I Ching: calendar, 1979, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: black cover, with loose ams leaves tipped in (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Calendar, 1980 - 1982, Accn. 2000-272; loose leaves (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Weekly planner, 1983, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: grey blue cover (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Year book, 1984, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: grey blue cover (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Year book, 1985, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: brown cover (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Year book, 1986, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: black cover (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Calendar, 1987, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: black cover (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Appointments, 1988, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v.: grey blue cover (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Engagement book, 1989, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v. (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Georgia O'Keefe one hundred flowers engagment calendar, 1990, Accn. 2000-272; 1 v. (Box 55, Folder 4)
- Series 8: Photographs
  - Postcards (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Pictures and photographs, including cover of Vanity Fair, Dec. 1987autographed by Bette Middler (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Photos - snapshots, 8"×10", 2 photos of Richard Thomas (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Black and White Photographs of Islas:4 8"×10" contact sheets, 3 4"×6"s, 1 8"×10", 1 8"×10" contact sheet with notes (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Snapshots (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Slides and Negatives (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Photograph, Accn. 2000-272 (Box 55, Folder 14)
- Series 9: Oversize
  - Normal XV doll (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - English 122 (Winter 1977)ASSU Course Guide Student Opinion Questionnaire (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous news and magazine clippings (1979-1990) (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Magazines, re: Ernest Hemingway (1960-1981) (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - List of names (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Watercolors for Islas's birthdays (1974-1977)by Nunni (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Conrado LaFarga: official documents (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Illustrations to Herman Melville's Moby Dick (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Artwork and Wall Hangings (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - 3 photographs, 2 pictures, letter from Janet Lewis (Box 50)
  - Dinkelspieal Award, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Border Regional Library Association, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Souls book cover (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Plaque from the 1990Chicano/Latino Graduating Class (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - The New Yorker, March 29, 1976magazine cover (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Matted print (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - poster for El Teatro Campesino's Corridos (1983) (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - The Rain God bookcover (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - reproduction of The Annunciation by Fra Filippo Lippi (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - print: Mujeres by Burciaga (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Ancient Egyptian Magic Calendar, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 6)
- Series 10. Computer files
  - Islas diskettes, Accn. 2000-272; 26 computer diskettes: 5.25 in. (Box 56, Folder 126)